oed.com 2019-11-11

# Oxford University Press - Privacy Policy

Last updated April 2018

Privacy Policy

Oxford University Press ("OUP") is committed to protecting your personal information and respecting data protection laws around the world. This privacy policy explains how we do this, and it applies to your use of OUP websites, products, and services. 

How we use your personal information  
  
We use personal information in order to promote and provide OUP products and services, to ensure the security of our websites, and to run our business. We have set out on **[this page](http://global.oup.com/privacy_info?cc=us)** more information on the categories of personal information that we collect, the specific ways in which that personal information is processed by us, the legal bases which permit us to do this, and the types of partners with whom we share your personal information.

In some cases where we ask for your personal information, we do so in order for us to fulfil your request or order (e.g. needing your address to send you your order). If you do not provide that personal information we will not be able to process your request or order.

Giving and withdrawing your consent, and updating your personal information  
  
Where your consent is required for us to process your personal information, we will ask for your consent at the point at which you provide your data.  You have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. You can also update your personal information at any time. If you wish to do either, contact us at [privacy@oup.com](mailto:privacy@oup.com).We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

Storing your personal information

Your personal information may be stored and processed outside of the country where it is collected, including outside of the European Economic Area. When transferring information to others, within the EEA or otherwise, we ensure that appropriate and suitable safeguards and technical measures are in place to protect your personal data. To do this, we make use of standard contractual clauses that have been approved by the European Commission, or we use an appropriate Privacy Shield certification or Binding Corporate Rules put in place by our suppliers, or we implement other similar measures required by laws around the world. A copy of the relevant mechanism can be provided for your review on request by sending an e-mail to our Data Privacy Officer at [privacy@oup.com](mailto:privacy@oup.com).We will only keep records of your personal information for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes for which we have collected it, and in order to comply with any statutory or regulatory obligations in relation to retention of records. We respect requests to stop processing your personal data for marketing purposes. This includes keeping a record of your request indefinitely so that we can respect your request in future.

Cookies  
  
We use cookies on our websites and similar technologies in our apps and other software.  Please see our [Cookie Policy](http://global.oup.com/cookiepolicy?cc=us "Global OUP CookiePolicy") for details of how this may apply to you. 

Your rights  
  
You have the right to request access to and rectification or erasure of personal information, the right to restrict processing of your personal information, and the right to object to processing of your personal information. You have the right to object to your personal information being processed on the grounds of OUP's legitimate interests. You have the right to object to us sending you direct marketing and profiling you for the purposes of direct marketing. You can contact us by email at [privacy@oup.com](mailto:privacy@oup.com) in relation to any of the rights described in this paragraph, or if you have any questions regarding this privacy policy.  You have the right to lodge a complaint regarding our processing of your personal information with a data protection supervisory authority in a country where you live, work, or where you believe a breach may have occurred. 

Contacting us

The data controller for our websites, products and services is The Chancellor, Masters and Scholars of the University of Oxford, trading as Oxford University Press, of Great Clarendon Street, Oxford OX2 6DP, United Kingdom, unless otherwise indicated on the website, product, service or form  through which you have provided your personal data to us.  For example, if you provided your personal data through the website www.oupe.es, the data controller is Oxford University Press España S.A. If you are unsure who your data controller is, or have other queries relating to this policy, OUP's Data Privacy Officer (the Data Protection Officer) can be reached at the same address or by email at [privacy@oup.com.](mailto:privacy@oup.com)
